Residential Life, Office of; Records ua743
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Department of Residential Life Records
1944-1985
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua743
4.5 cubic ft.
This collection is made up of the inactive records from the Department of Residential Life and its predecessor, the Office of Residences.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
The Housing Office was established in 1959 to take over responsibility for overseeing student housing from the Student Personnel Office. The name later changed to the Office of Residences, and it is currently known as the Department of Residential Life.
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily documents the procedures used by the Department of Residential Life to manage student housing on campus. Materials in this collection include: annual reports, Residential Life staff orientation documents and policy manuals, pamphlets with information about residence halls, administrative memoranda, residence statistics, newsletters, floor plans, schedules, and meeting minutes from the Living Area Affairs Commission.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.
Education, Higher--Administration; Student housing; Dormitories; Administrative records; Annual reports; employees' manuals; Newletters; UAlbany Student Affairs; State University of New York at Albany
- Knapton Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Petre Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Moore Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Housing Policies and Memoranda, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Meeting Minutes, 1976-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Housing Sign-up Files, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- International Students, 1970 September (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Resident Assistants, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Statistical Analysis, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Walden Council, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Welcome Letter, 1969 February (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Withdrawls, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Women's Hours, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Policy Documentation File, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Resident Newsletter, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Scaring Memos, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Seyfarth Memos, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Seyfarth Memos (Sept.-Jan.), 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Staff Orientation, 1968 December (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Staff Recruitment, 1969 January (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Departmental Memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Annual Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- R.A. Assignments, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Petri Memos, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Memoranda, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Greek Housing Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Doyle Memos, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Fairbanks Memos, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Secor Memos, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Central Office Files, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Computing Center Files, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Recess Housing, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Student Housing Forms and Memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Knapton Memos, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Director Memos, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Policies and Procedures Manual, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Student Forms, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Departmental Memoranda, 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- R.A. Selection Memoranda, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Greek Housing, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Health Service Memorandums, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Housing Seminar, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Corresondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Key Deposit Forms, 1968 September (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Knapton Memorandums, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Office Memoranda, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Edsall Memorandums, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Fairbanks Memorandums, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Food Service, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Graduate Housing Plans, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Miller Momorandums, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Brubacher Hall, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Collins Memorandums, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- L.A.A.C., 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Contract Card Brochure Design, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Resident Hall Damage Files, 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Reference Files [1 of 3], 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Reference Files [2 of 3], 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Reference Files [3 of 3], 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Office of Residents Policies and Procedures Manual, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Policies and Procedures Manual, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Housing Registration Files [1 of 2], 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Housing Registration Files [2 of 2], 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Kosher Foods, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- L.A.A.C., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Office Memoranda, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Central Office Staff, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Bike Storage, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Drug Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Graduation Lists, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Housing Procedures, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Materials for Students, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- R.A Policy and Procedures Manual, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Residence Director Materials, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Director Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Statistical Analysis Report, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Theta Xi Omega Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Upsilon Phi Sigma Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Beta Zeta Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Chi Sigma Theta Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Gamma Kappa Phi Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Kappa Chi Rho Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Kappa Delta, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Psi Gamma Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Phi Delta Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Sigma Alpha Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Sigma Phi Sigma Sorority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Board Plan Proposal, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Central Council, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Brubacher Hall, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Wightman Memorandums, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Spring Housing Procedures, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- R.A Assignments, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Petre Memoramdums, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Marcolini Memos, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Lockbox, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Moore Memorandums, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Miscellanous, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Personnel, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Alpha Lambda Chi Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Alpha Pi Alpha, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Beta Phi Sigma Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Gamma Delta Chi Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- E.E. Potter Club Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Kappa Beta Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Sigma Tali Beta Fraternity, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Central Council, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Brubacher Hall, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Faculty, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- EOP, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Edsall Memos, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Drugs, Sex, Etc., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Paid, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Memoranda and Proposals, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Greek Housing, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Central Staff News, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Statistical Reports, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Student Life Procedures, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Spring and Summer Session Housing, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Graduated Students, 1974 May (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Handicapped Students, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- On-Campus Housing Procedures and Forms [1 of 2], 1969-1964 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- On-Campus Housing Procedures and Forms [2 of 2], 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Pierce and Sayles Floor Plans, Undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Recycling, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Staff Orientation, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- R.A. Handbook, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Judicial Advisors Manual, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Handouts and Memoranda, 1972-1983 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Professional Staff Policies and Procedures Manual, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Summer Conference Housing Petre, 1972 July (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Computer Manual, 1970 April (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Summer Conference Operation #1, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Summer Conference, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Brochures and Calendars, 1944-1983 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Residence Hall Staff, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Office of Residence Life, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Basic Helping Skills Techniques for the Paraprofessional, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Politics and Procedures Manual for Professional Staff, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Policies and Procedures for SUNYA Resident Assistants, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Office of Residents- Policies and Procedures Manual, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Office of Residence Management- Policies and Procedures Manual, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Office of Residence Management, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Office of Residential Life Misc., 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Procedures Notebooks, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Resident Assistant Materials [1 of 2], 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Resident Assistant Materials [2 of 2], 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Annual Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Annual Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Annual Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Additional Annual Reports [1 of 2], 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Additional Annual Reports [2 of 2], 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Annual Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Additional Annual Reports [1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Additional Annual Reports [2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Annual Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Additional Annual Reports [1 of 2], 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Additional Annual Reports [2 of 2], 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Annual Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Office of Residence Annual Report, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Additional Annual Reports [1 of 2], 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Additional Annual Reports [2 of 2], 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Policies and Procedures Manual, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Policies and Procedures Notebook, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Residence Handbook, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Procedures Notebook, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)